本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
■
职能  翻译
阿好
我们被监视着
We are being watched.
王小麦
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
卫老哥
紫玉
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
幸田实果子
maenad
兔妈
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
蓬蓬裙
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything...
小小
板凳小早
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considers these people irrelevant.
■
职能  校对  阿好
职能  压制  灰灰是菇凉
我们不
We don't.
■
职能  时间轴
凭陵新月
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
雪贵人
没有影子
芒果树叶
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
特效
灰灰
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
总监
阿好
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第四季 第四集
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem, yo.
多米尼克要在48小时内看到线路正常运行
Dominic wants the new network up and running in the next 48.
有什么需要帮忙的  警探
What can I do for you, Detective?
我需要点信息  有个黑帮叫"兄弟会"
I'm looking for information on a gang called "Brotherhood."
他们的头目叫多米尼克
It's run by a guy named Dominic.
我没见过他
We haven't met yet.
野心勃勃  老谋深算
Ambitious and smart.
最好避开这个多米尼克
Maybe steer clear of this Dominic.
交易开始
Deal's going down.
亚美尼亚人已经到了
The Armenians are already here.
小心有诈
Watch your back in case things get jumpy.
到学校了吗  里瑟先生
Are you at the school, Mr. Reese?
上学读书当真非我所长
Academics really aren't my thing.
这事儿应该你做才对啊  教授
Maybe you should be on this assignment, Professor.
我自己这里还有事儿呢
I have quite a few assignments of my own.
我有论文要批改
Including papers to grade--
现在没了
Or I had papers to grade.
得去告诉你的学生
Gonna have to tell your students,
你的狗吃了人家的作业
your dog ate their homework.
我们这位新号码在小学
So our new number's in this grade school?
其中之一是的
One of them, yes.
特蕾西·布克  八岁
Tracie Booker, eight years old.
她的号码
We received her number
和她十四岁的哥哥马尔科姆的号码同时跳出
along with that of her 14-year-old brother, Malcolm.
发了  看你手机
Here, check your phone.
可能是家庭问题
Could be dealing with a domestic issue.
找到他们妈妈了吗
Have you located their mom?
哈森大街1412号  里克岛
1412 Hazen Street, Rikers Island.
恐怕他们的母亲在监狱里
I'm afraid their mother's in prison
罪名是非法持械
on a weapons violation.
父亲已故  没发现任何亲属
The father's deceased and I have yet to locate any relatives.
那他们都在政府系统中了
So they're in the system.
寄养儿童
Foster children.
看来他们的生活中  那所学校是唯一不变的
It seems that school is the one constant in their lives.
今天就变了
Not today.
到处找不到特蕾西
There's no sign of Tracie anywhere.
也许她的同学会知道她在哪里
Perhaps a fellow student knows where she is?
没有人肯跟警察开口的
No one's gonna get caught dead talking to a cop,
在这一片不可能
not in this neighborhood.
有意思了  我可是轻而易举
Funny, I didn't have any problems
就让马尔科姆的朋友开口了
getting Malcolm's friends to talk.
当然了  他们是有人问我要号码来着
Although, one of them did ask me for my number.
你找到马尔科姆了吗  肖女士
Have you located Malcolm, Ms. Shaw?
没有
Negative.
他今天没上学
He didn't show for school today.
看来你不得不施展魅力了  约翰
Looks like you're gonna have to work your magic after all, John.
打扰一下
Excuse me,
你们今天看到特蕾西·布克了吗
have any of you seen Tracie Booker today?
条子  我们走吧  姑娘们
5-0. Let's go, girls.
等等
Wait...
好吧  我陪你们玩这个
All right, I'll play you for it.
跳房子
Hopscotch.
别闪了你的老腰
Don't go hurting yourself, old man.
想要我们透信儿
Want us to drop a dime?
给点钱钱啦
It'sgonnacost ya.
好消息  哈罗德  我有消息
Good news, Harold, I got a lead.
坏消息  我还要小额备用金
Bad news, I need more petty cash.
我得提醒你  里瑟先生  我们现在的存款
Need I remind you, Mr. Reese, that our recent deposit
必须撑好长一段时间啊
has to last for a very long time.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
我得提醒你每天早上送特蕾西来上学
Malcolm walks Tracie to school every morning.
我在沿着他们的路线走
I'm retracing their route.
两个孩子分别上不同的学校  彼此离得很远
The children go to separate schools across town from each other.
要天一亮就出发才能准时到校
They'd have to leave at the crack of dawn to be on time.
看来我们是迟到了
I think we're the ones who are too late.
刚看到一犯罪现场
Just stumbled on a crime scene.
但愿孩子们不在这儿
Let's hope the kids aren't here.
黑帮枪战
We have a gang-related shooting.
三名成年非裔美国人和三名亚美尼亚人身亡
Three adult, African-americans and three Armenians, deceased.
两名男性受多处枪伤
Two males with multiple gsws.
打扰一下
Excuse me...
你破坏证据了
you're tampering with our evidence.
莱利警探  凶案组的
Detective Riley, homicide.
伦诺克斯特工  缉毒局的
Agent Lennox, DEA.
这位是我的搭档  汤姆森
This is my partner, Thomsen.
她出什么事儿了
What exactly happened her?
通常我会说读报告去
Normally, I'd say you can read it in our report.
不过既然你如此彬彬有礼  我也不吝分享了
But since you asked so nice, I'm willing to share.
别客气  莱利
Knock yourself out, Riley.
我上报去
I'll call it in.
字幕
No colors, no bandanas, and no ID.
是兄弟会
It's the Brotherhood.
你听说过
You've heard of them.
看来他们跟亚美尼亚人有毒品交易
It appears they were making a drug trade with the Armenians.
好像唯一交易成功的只有子弹
Looks like the only thing they traded were bullets.
出什么岔子了呢
What went wrong?
我听说兄弟会的老大态度非常强硬
I've heard the Brotherhood's leader strikes a hard bargain.
也许亚美尼亚人不喜欢他的谈判方法
Maybe the Armenians didn't like his negotiation tactics.
多米尼克
Dominic.
缉毒局数月来一直在查他
DEA's been trying to lay eyes on him for months.
没有进展  你呢
No luck. You?
没有
No.
多米尼克老谋深算
Dominic's smart.
他让手下出面负责毒品交易  承担风险
He let's his men handle the drug deals and the risk.
还有谁活着
Who's left standing?
一个亚美尼亚人
Armenian.
恐怕他也熬不过今晚
Doubt he'll make it through the night.
还有一个打手被射伤
And a piece of muscle with a gunshot wound.
是多米尼克的人
One of Dominic's boys.
不幸的是  他也不肯开口
Unfortunately, he's not talking either.
看来兄弟会雇他不是冲着他能说会道
Guessing the Brotherhood didn't hire him for his conversation.
我还有个闹不明白的地方  莱利
I got a puzzle here, Riley.
我找到了两辆车
I got two four-seater vehicles,
八个黑帮分子
eight gangsters,
和一大袋海洛因
and one large bag of heroin.
没找到买毒品的钱
Only piece missing is the drug money.
没错
Exactly.
我们把这栋楼和那两辆车翻了个遍  就是找不到
We tossed this building and the cars, it's not here.
谁拿走了钱呢
So who took it?
按海洛因的行情
Given the street value of the heroin,
这个问题价值50万美元
I'd say that's the $1/2 million question.
我看不管谁拿走了钱  都活不到今天晚上了
I'm betting whoever it is won't make it till sundown.
伦诺克斯特工  过来看一下
Agent Lennox, got something you should see.
警探  我们有麻烦了
Detective, we have a problem.
我通过政府发放的交通卡
I've managed to track the booker children
找到了布克家的小孩
via their government issued metro cards.
他们从第五大道车站出的站
They exited the 5th Avenue Station.
第五大道
5th Avenue.
你不认为这些孩子
You don't suppose the children
逃学是为了去购物吧
ditched school to go shopping?
真是凑巧
Funny you should mention that.
他们正在买新衣服
They're buying new clothes.
看起来是这两个孩子
It would appear that the children
偷了毒品钱
have stolen the drug money.
你能先拦下他们吗
Think you can intercept them before anyone else does?
我尽量
I'll do my best.
我要去洗手间
I need to use the bathroom.
你不能憋着吗
Can't you hold it?
等等
Hold up.
马尔科姆  特蕾西
Malcolm? Tracie?
你拦下他们了吗  教授
You got the kids, Professor?
我跟丢了
I've lost them.
希望别是永远地丢了
I hope it's not for good.
这两孩子比想象中聪明得多
The children have proven more resourceful than expected.
但他们吸引太多注意了
But their antics have raised more than a few eyebrows.
这么发展下去  用不了多久
At this rate, it won't be long
兄弟会就会找到他们了
before the Brotherhood catches up with them.
还有亚美尼亚人
Not to mention the Armenians.
也许你该找缉毒局帮帮忙
Perhaps you should enlist the help of the DEA.
我已经告诉伦诺克斯特工马尔科姆和特蕾西的事了
I already told Agent Lennox about Malcolm and Tracie.
已经发布了对两个孩子的协查通报
There's a B.O.L.O. out for the kids now.
我都不敢想象如果黑帮比我们
I shudder to think what will happen
先找到这些孩子会发生什么
if the gangs find them before we do.
那咱们就先下手为强
So let's beat the perps to the punch.
先阻止他们
Stop them first.
你有什么计划
What exactly do you have in mind?
给肖找了点活干
Got a little job for Shaw.
这活儿需要点医疗经验
It requires some medical experience.
而你该去见位老朋友
And I think it's time you caught up with an old friend.
你好  哈罗德
Hello, Harold.
我得承认  我很怀念和你对弈
I must confess, I've missed our little chess matches.
你最近忙什么呢
Where have you been keeping yourself?
这么说吧  我决定重返校园了
Guess you could say that I've decided to go back to school.
你在学术界定能如鱼得水
I imagine you'd fit in rather well in academia.
可你却跑来这儿了
And yet, here you are.
得了
Please,
我知道丢失了毒品钱
I've heard about the missing drug money.
被几个小贼偷了
and the little thieves who stole it.
约翰正在想办法保护那些孩子
John's trying to get the children to safety
但是他需要时间
but he needs time.
你要我再一次扮演次仲裁人
And you want me to play mediator again?
算我们欠你
We would be in your debt.
你们已经欠了
You already are.
我可以控制亚美尼亚人
I can control the Armenians.
不过兄弟会你们得自己解决
But you'll have to deal with the Brotherhood yourself.
约翰认为你已经
John seemed to think that you've tried to
联系过他们的老大了
contact their leader.
多米尼克  他很难找到
Dominic, he's proven to be elusive.
也许比你还难找  哈罗德
Perhaps even more elusive than you, Harold.
我只是个搭地铁的
I'm just a man on a subway train.
不起眼的老师
A humble teacher?
我角色我扮演过
I played that role once myself.
而约翰现在是警探了
And John's a detective now.
我很好奇  为什么突然转换身份
I'm curious, why the sudden career shift?
有什么事改变了
Something has changed.
彻底改变了
Something fundamental.
我不是在说
And I'm not just referring
你和你的朋友的行动
to how you and your friends operate.
我觉得你知道发生了什么
I think you know what's happening.
我觉得你应该欠我的  应该告诉我真相
And I think you owe it to me to tell me the truth.
时代虽然改变了
Times may have changed,
但是恐怕你我都行走在黑暗中了
but I'm afraid we're both in the dark.
华尔街站到了
This is Wall Street.
下一站富尔顿街
Next stop is Fulton Street.
请不要站在关闭的车门前
Stand clear of the closing doors.
你主动申请了个七杀案
You volunteered us for a septuple homicide?
七杀是死了七个人
Septuple as in seven?
是你要我好好工作的
You're the one who told me to take this job seriously.
要努力工作  记得吗
Be hands on, remember?
记得  那是叫你努力搞好文件工作
Yeah, then you can get your "hands on" some of this paperwork.
注意风度啊
Where are your manners?
你没看到伦洛克斯特工在等我吗
Can't you see that Agent Lennox is waiting for me?
她不是唯一一个找你的人
She's not the only one looking for you.
你那朋友  林克
Your friend, Link?
你逮捕的那个兄弟会副手
The Brotherhood lieutenant you arrested--
十分钟前被放出来了
released from the joint ten minutes ago.
兄弟会找了个未成年的混混
Brotherhood found an underage corner boy
去替他背黑锅
to take the fall for him.
那孩子把罪都认了
Kid confessed everything.
林克只受到轻罪指控
Link's getting off with a misdemeanor charge.
"事后从犯"
"Accessory after the fact."
我稍后再对付他
I'll deal with him later.
搞不好他会先对付你
Not if he deals with you first.
有空吗  警探
Got a minute, Detective?
信任真是件有趣的事  莱利
Trust is a funny thing, Riley.
我稍微调查了你一下
I did a little digging on you.
你在当缉毒警之前没什么资料
Couldn't find much before your stint in narco.
我觉得你不像个凶案警探
You know, you don't strike me as a homicide detective.
也许是你查得不够努力
Well, maybe you're not looking hard enough.
真意外  考虑到你的经历
Surprising, given someone of your experience.
你从安纳波利斯毕业  班级第一
You graduated from Annapolis, top of your class.
在美国海军服役两期  表现优异
Served two tours, with distinction, for the U.S. Navy
之后加入了缉毒局
before joining the DEA.
没错  我也做了点调查
Yeah, I did a little digging too.
所以你是打算站在那儿审问我
So you just gonna stand there and interrogate me?
还是讨论一下案子
Or would you like to discuss this case?
你对兄弟会有何了解
How well do you know the Brotherhood?
我逮捕了他们的一个成员
I arrested one of their soldiers.
那你应该知道他们的网络无所不在
Then you know their network's as pervasive as it is deadly.
他们不守什么地盘
They don't believe in territories,
他们的线人渗透了每个街区
they've got informants on every block,
而且  恐怕是
and, I'm afraid to say,
也渗透了各执法部门
in every law enforcement organization.
缉毒局认为局里有内鬼
The DEA believes there's a mole in our agency.
有人为多米尼克工作
A man working for Dominic.
-知道是谁吗  -不知道
- Any idea who? - No.
坦白说  这让我和我的搭档
Frankly, it has me and my partner
开始怀疑我们的同事了
looking sideways at our colleagues.
你现在却还是信任我
Yet you're trusting me now.
我说过  信任是件有趣的事
Like I said, trust is a funny thing.
我只感觉你与众不同
Something tells me you're different.
你充满热忱
You care.
既然你跟我分享了关于孩子的线索
And since you shared your lead with me on the kids...
这是今天早些时候拍的
This was taken earlier today.
什么孩子偷了50万美元之后
What kind of kids steal $1/2 million
第一件事是去买新衣服
and the first thing they buy are new clothes?
也许他们要去什么有着装要求的地方
Maybe they're going somewhere with a dress code.
他们买其他东西了吗
They buy anything else?
他们用现金买了一个手机
They purchased a phone with cash.
你能追踪吗
Can you trace it?
只需要有序列号就行
All I need is a serial number.
已经申请搜查令了
Already applied for a warrant.
几小时就能搞定
Should only take a couple of hours.
恐怕我们没有几个小时了  里瑟先生
I'm afraid we may not have a couple of hours, Mr. Reese.
幸好我们认识一位
Then it's a good thing we know someone
能黑进孩子手机的人
who can hack the kids' phone.
这比以前要难办得多
It's considerably more difficult than it used to be.
我之前有手机生产商的资料
I was up on the cell phone providers
但跟图书馆一起失去了
but I lost that capability along with the library.
我必须从头开始
I'll have to start from scratch.
那就期盼肖有好运气吧
Let's hope Shaw's having better luck.
我们在医院吗
We at the hospital?
计划有变
Change of plans.
我们不去普通医院了
We're not going to general.
什么
What?
反正医疗水平也不怎么样
Care's sub-par anyway.
你不是急救人员
You ain't no EMT.
你是警察吗
You a cop?
你有名字吗  硬汉
You got a name, tough guy?
哥们都叫我迷你
Boys call me Mini.
因为我块头大
'cause I'm big.
好吧  大块头
Okay, supersize.
我要你给你哥们林克打电话
I want you to call your pal, Link.
问出他的位置
Get his location.
干你们这行的
Guy like you in your line of work...
能认出真正的杀手  是吧
You know a killer when you see one, right?
快点
Hurry.
你怎么知道这个号码的
Yeah? How'd you get this number?
林克  我是迷你
You, Link, it's Mini.
迷你
Mini?
听说你跟亚美尼亚人有点麻烦
The word is you got into some trouble with the Armenians.
一切都在掌控中
Nothing that couldn't be handled.
你在哪儿
Where you at?
要去百老汇街和里德街路口
Boys are gonna be there at Broadway and Reed.
十分钟后
Ten minutes.
好啦  猛男  这事儿很简单
All right, tough guy, I'm gonna make this real simple for you.
照我说的做  你就能活
You do what I say, you live.
下车
Get out.
马上
Now.
别打什么鬼主意
And don't get any ideas,
扳机比你动作快
this trigger is faster than your first.
我通过手机定位到了孩子
I've located the children via their cell phones.
奇怪的是  他们好像往一个大律所去了
Oddly, they appear to be headed toward a large law office.
地址是什么
What's the address?
还有多远  我的脚痛
How much further? My feet hurt.
跟你说了要买舒服点的鞋
I told you to buy sensible shoes.
为什么我们不能像普通人那样从前门进去
Why can't we just go through the front like normal people?
因为普通人不会背着一大包现金  知道吗
'cause normal people don't carry bags of cash, all right?
前门有保安
Front's got security.
从那里进去  他们会把钱拿走
We go up there, they take our money.
那这也不是我们的钱啊
But it's not really our money.
被我们拿了钱的那些人
Those guys we took it from--
都死了
Are dead.
好啦  他们不能伤害我们
A'ight, they can't hurt us.
过来  这边
Come on! This way!
动作快点
Make it quick.
我们有两分钟  顶多三分钟
We got about two minutes, three minutes tops
然后警察就该来了
till the cherries roll in.
我把他们扫射出来
I'll flush 'em out.
小特  不管发生什么
All right, T, whatever happens,
别要放开我的手
don't let go of my hand, a'ight?
跟紧我
Stick together.
该死
Damn.
看来我惹恼你朋友了
I think I made your friends angry.
那是咱们的人吗
That our man?
她抓了咱们的弟兄  得把他救回来
Man, she got our boy. We gotta retrieve him.
你知道多米尼克的规矩
You know Dominic's rules.
别理他  先追孩子
Just forget him. Let's go after this green.
这俩兄妹跑不远
Little man and his sister can't be too far.
我是莱利警探
Detective Riley.
我是来帮你们的
I'm here to help.
我可以送你们回家
I'll get you back home safely.
我们早就没有家了  好吗
We ain't got a home, all right? Not anymore.
小特  我给你的水枪还在不
T, you still got that squirt gun I gave you?
小心  这可是胡椒喷雾
Watch out, it's pepper spray.
我看你遇上对手了  莱利
I think you met your match, Riley.
你俩要想安全走出这个停车场
You kids wanna make it out of this garage,
就得乖乖听话
You'll do as you're told.
你该换个行业啊  伦诺克斯
You might have a new calling Lennox.
找到孩子了吗  警探  我过来接你
You got the kids, Detective? I'm coming to get you now.
伦诺克斯已经开始怀疑了
Lennox is already asking questions.
不能冒险暴露身份
I can't risk breaking cover.
你想扮幼儿园保安  请便
You wanna play kindergarten cop, suit yourself.
得打电话请求支援
Gotta call for back up.
正在过来了
Call on the way.
我抓的那个兄弟会成员
That Brotherhood soldier I arrested,
之前忘了说他名叫林克
I forgot to mention his name was Link.
你是说  你是全世界唯一一个
Telling me you're the only other person
兄弟会盼你死  甚至超过盼这两孩子死
the Brotherhood wants to gun down more than these kids?
我是说  我们得尽快回到路面上
I'm telling you we should get off the streets right now.
那是新款的任天堂
That's the new wii!
这是什么地方
Who's place is this?
上周我在这有个活儿
I worked a job here last week.
什么工作
What kind of job?
最好不要多问的那种工作
The kind it's better not to ask about.
缉毒局在城市的那头  但他们正派支援过来
DEA's office is across town, but they're sending back up.
你确定这样安全吗
You sure it's safe?
内鬼怎么办
What about that mole?
我打给了我的搭档汤姆森
I called my partner, Thomsen.
我信任他
He's the one guy I trust.
我是伦诺克斯特工  你们可以叫我艾丽卡
I'm Agent Lennox, but you can call me Erica.
我在缉毒局工作  你们知道缉毒局吗
I work for the DEA, do you know what that means?
我们家有电视
We got TV.
好吧
Okay.
我需要你告诉我毒品交易的事
I need you to tell me about the drug exchange.
你俩肯定有人看到了什么
One of you must've seen something.
看到又怎么样
What if I did?
意味着我要去法庭上指控兄弟会吗
Does that mean I have to testify against the Brotherhood?
现在我们只想立案调查他们
Right now, we're just trying to make a case against them.
那些钱怎么办
What about the money?
我们必须把它作为证据没收
We'll have to admit that into evidence.
不行  我们需要钱
You can't, we need it.
要钱做什么
Need it for what?
把我妈妈救回来
To get our mom back.
他们的母亲在里克岛监狱
Their mother's in Rikers
罪名是非法持有未注册枪械
for an unregistered weapons charge.
都是她那个傻逼男友的错
It was her punk-ass boyfriend that was the problem.
她要甩了他  他就又吵又骂
She tried to throw him out and he got all loud and mean.
邻居就报警了
So the neighbors called the cops?
警察发现了未注册的枪支
The found the unregistered gun.
她根本没开枪
She ain't even shoot it.
还是把她抓走了
Put her away anyway.
所以你俩就进了政府系统
And you two went into the system.
我和哥哥在不同的人家
We ain't even in the same house.
只有早上上学路上
Only time we get to see each other
才能见到彼此
is when I walk t to school in the morning.
如果我妈妈从里克岛监狱出来
But if our mom gets out of Rikers,
我们就能一家团聚了
we can be a family again.
所以你才拿走了那些钱吗
So that's why you took the money?
我查过了
I got research.
有很多因未注册枪支被抓的人
Plenty of people have been caught with unregistered guns
都不用去坐牢
and haven't gone to jail for it.
我们只要有个好律师
A good lawyer. It's what we need.
名校毕业的  高手
I'm talking Ivy league. Dream team.
但那种律师  得花大钱
But a lawyer like that, you gotta pay to play.
要预付
Upfront.
你们买新衣服是为了讨好律师
So you bought new clothes to impress an attorney.
有几个大牌律师愿意
You know any prize lawyers gonna take on
帮两个被领养的孩子
two foster kids from the hood?
我们懂了
We get it.
你只想挽回自己的家
You want your family back.
但偷走毒资解决不了任何问题
But stolen drug money's not gonna solve anyone's problems.
当男子汉  得有计划
Wanna be the man, you gotta have a plan.
我们不会交出钱的
We're not giving up that money.
肖女士  纽约警局刚发布了全境通告
Ms. Shaw, NYPD just put out an APB
搜索你偷的那辆车
on that stolen vehicle you're driving.
刚才偷的  现在没有了
Was driving. Not anymore.
约翰还在当保姆吗
John still baby-sitting?
他在等缉毒局的支援
He's awaiting the DEA's backup.
你觉得缉毒局真的会保护那俩孩子
Do you really think the DEA can protect those kids
对抗兄弟会吗
against the Brotherhood?
也许我们该听取以利亚的建议
Perhaps we need to do what Mr. Elias suggested.
和多米尼克谈谈
Talk to Dominic.
好吧  我们运气不错
Well, lucky for us...
我知道谁能找到他
I got an idea who knows where to find him.
好了  咱们走走吧
All right, let's take a walk.
你要把多米尼克的事都告诉我
You're gonna tell me everything you know about Dominic.
走吧
Come on.
别紧张  我朋友们很快就会来的
Relax. My friends will be here soon.
你手机上有《我的世界》吗
You got Minecraft on that phone?
我有个侄女跟你差不多大
I got a niece your age.
我肯定你能找到喜欢的游戏玩
I'm sure you'll be able to find something to play with on there.
你外表凶  人很好
You know, you're nicer than you look.
孩子好像挺喜欢你
Kid seems to like you.
让我忍不住想  我真的可以有所成就
Makes me think I might actually be making a difference.
我猜猜
Let me guess...
你很久没有过这种感觉了
You haven't felt that way in a while.
我能帮他们  但缉毒局有太多繁文缛节
I could help them, but the DEA has so much red tape.
无能为力
Hands are tied.
要一直等到他们录完口供  交出证据
Till they make a statement and hand over evidence.
恐怕是这样
I'm afraid so.
我知道你要说什么  免了
Look, I know what you're gonna say, all right, so save it.
我不会告诉你钱在哪里的
I'm not telling you where that money is.
你不用说
You won't have to.
我们总会找到的
We'll find it anyway.
你以为我们怎么找到你和你妹妹的
How do you think we found you and your sister?
你们有监控设备
Y'all got cameras and stuff.
是啊  追踪你不会花太久的
Yeah, won't take long to retrace your steps.
这么说我现在该做笔交易吗
Saying I should make a deal now?
趁你还有筹码可以讨价还价
While you still have something to barter with.
你犯了一些致命的错误  马尔科姆
You've made some very big mistakes, Malcolm.
那群黑帮朝我们扫射时
Yeah, I kind of realized that when those gangsters
我就意识到了
were shooting at us.
你能阻止他们吗
Can you stop them?
我会努力的
I'm gonna try.
但你之前已经逮捕一个了
But you've already arrested one of them before.
没错
I did,
但兄弟会利用街头小混混
but the Brotherhood uses corner boys,
那些比你大不了多少的孩子
kids not much older than you,
替他们蹲监狱了
to get them out of prison.
明白了
Figures.
每个人都有自己的立场  我为什么要相信你
Look, everybody got an angle, why should I trust you?
因为我身处你和他们之间
'Cause I'm the one standing between you and them.
马尔科姆  你说你是男子汉  有计划
Malcolm, you say you're "the man with the plan,"
但我看到的只是一个
but all I've seen is a thief
差点害死妹妹的贼
that's almost got his sister killed.
你想当男子汉吗
You wanna be the man?
先照顾好你的家人
Start taking care of your family.
要是有什么不测
Anything happens...
你照顾好小特
You take care of T.
答应我
Promise?
我向你保证
I give you my word.
所有钱都在那里
All the money's there.
除了我们买衣服花掉的
Except for what we spent on clothes.
我相信缉毒局能理解
I'm sure the DEA will understand.
你做得很对
You're doing the right thing.
支援随时会来
Back up will be here any minute.
谢了
Thanks.
带你妹妹去一下卫生间  好吗
Get your sister and make sure she uses the bathroom, okay?
孩子很聪明  汤姆森会来接的
Kid's smart. Thomsen'll pick it up.
我们先确保冲出去
We need to make it out of here first.
我去看一下
I'll do a sweep.
我也去吧
I should go too.
以防兄弟会的人等着
In case the Brotherhood's waiting.
你担心我吗  警探
You worried about me, Detective?
没你帮助  我也走到了今天
I made it this far without your help.
我能搞定
I think I'll manage.
好了  迷你  坐吧
All right, Mini, sit.
自己拷到管子上
Cuff yourself to the pipe.
我们在哪儿
Where are we?
得看情况了
It depends.
告诉我想知道的事  就是休息区
You tell me what I want to know, it's a pit-stop.
不告诉
You don't...
那就是你的安息区
it's your final resting place.
多米尼克在哪儿
Now where's Dominic?
你要怎样  小姑娘
What you gonna do, little girl?
打我一顿拷问我吗
You gonna beat it out of me?
难道你不这样吗
Isn't that what you would do?
何必多问
Why bother asking?
你和我  我们不是一类人
You and me, we ain't even close to the same.
我不知道
I don't know about that.
我有种预感你能忍受疼痛
I got a hunch you can take the pain.
甚至乐在其中  就像我
You might even enjoy it. Like me.
那我们要做朋友吗
So now we gonna be friends?
看上去你可以稍微利用下
Seems like you could use a few.
你的同伴知道我抓了你
Your boys know I have you
多米尼克怎么没派人来
so how come Dominic hasn't sent anyone?
也许因为他知道我自己能解决
Maybe 'cause he knows I can handle my own.
也许吧
Maybe.
也许你只是不值得让他们找你
Or maybe you're just not worth the gas it takes to find you.
你在休克的第一阶段
You're in the first stages of shock.
出汗  细脉  失去血色
Sweaty, thready pulse, loss of color.
你现在要么死撑到血流光
Now, you can either stall until you bleed out,
要么告诉我多米尼克在哪
Or you can just tell me where Dominic is.
我要是说了  你觉得我会怎样
If I tell you, what do you think will happen to me?
还不是死在另一个地下室
Just end up in another basement.
你告诉我他在哪
You give me his location,
我就放你出去
I will get you out of dodge.
说吧  迷你  放聪明点
Come on, Mini, be smart.
游戏玩久一点
Play the long game.
像我这样的人  游戏玩不久
Ain't no long game for guys like me.
只是游戏
Just the game.
不管他妈怎么做都一样
Doesn't make a damn bit of a difference what you do.
为啥做都一样
Or who you do it for.
多米尼克也一样
Dominic ain't no different.
和其他人没区别
Just another man like all the rest.
多米尼克似乎要比你说得聪明
Sounds like this Dominic's a lot smarter than that.
最多几年  他就会下台
Couple years on top, he'll burn out.
或者送命
Or get wasted.
只有一条真理
Only one rule:
我们最终都难逃一死
We all die in the end.
伦诺克斯特工已经走好一会了
Agent Lennox's been gone awhile.
她是不是遇到麻烦了
Think she ran into trouble?
那女人之前肯定
Got a feeling that woman's stared trouble
经历过不少风浪
in the face more than a few times.
我想她没事的
I'm sure she's fine.
怎么了  莱奈尔
What's up, Lionel?
你可以请  我吃牛排来谢我
Yeah, you can--uh--thank me with a prime rib,
或者双烤土豆
Maybe some twice-baked potatoes...
你是在点餐呢
You placing a dinner order,
还是有什么事
Or is there a reason for your call?
你硬塞给我的那桩七杀案
You know that septuple homicide you saddled me with?
我在一部手机上发现条线索
I got a lead off one of the cell phones.
有个电话号码
A number.
兄弟会的人在凶案现场打了这个电话
Brotherhood banger called it from the scene of the crime.
所以呢
So?
所以  你不想和多米尼克对话吗
So didn't you want to have a chat with Dominic?
这可能是他的号码
This could be his number.
但你只有一次机会
But you'll only get to call it once.
那就打打看
Better make that call then.
你怎么会有这个手机
Where'd you get that phone?
伦诺克斯特工给我的  怎么了
Agent Lennox gave it to me, why?
怎么了  搭档
Is there a problem, partner?
看来缉毒缉局的确有兄弟会内鬼
Seems the DEA does have a mole working for the brotherhood.
伦诺克斯特工骗了我们
Agent Lennox double-crossed us.
你还保证呢
Gave me your word huh?
这么说是没有支援了
So we don't have back up.
有支援  只不过要久一点
We do, it's just gonna take a little longer than expected.
撑住  我马上来
Sit tight. I'm on my way.
你最好快点
You'd better make it quick.
我们被包围了
We're surrounded.
有缉毒局内线的最新情况吗
Have you heard from our snitch in the DEA, lately?
没有  不过她说警察和孩子就在这里
No, but she said the cop and the kid are here.
闭上嘴  就饶你一命
Keep your mouth shut and you'll live.
芬奇  弗斯科预计多久到
Finch, you got an ETA on Fusco?
八分钟  视交通状况而定
Eight minutes based on current traffic patterns.
你能把兄弟会拖到那时么
Can you hold off the Brotherhood until then?
正有此意
That's the plan.
我想伦诺克斯女士拿到毒品钱了
I imagine Ms. Lennox has recovered the drug money by now.
如果她是内鬼  兄弟会为什么
But if she's their mole, then why is the Brotherhood
还在追杀孩子
still after the kids?
可能她不止骗了我们
Perhaps we're not the only ones she's double-crossed.
所以她留下了手机
Would explain why she left her cell.
兄弟会就追踪不到她了
So the Brotherhood can't trace her.
很不幸  我们也一样
Nor can we, unfortunately.
五十万足够让人失踪了
$1/2 million is more than enough to disappear for good.
我们就没这么幸运
We're not so lucky.
兄弟会拿不到钱不会罢手的
Brotherhood's not backing down without their money.
退而求其次了
What about the next best thing?
肖女士  你有多米尼克的位置了吗
Ms. Shaw, have you located dominic?
还没
Not exactly.
不过我和大块头谈了谈
But I had a chat with our big friend.
留他一个人
left him alone to cool off.
他那些冒火的同伙没来找他
That guy's angry his boys ain't come looking for him.
看来救名打手不是他们的首要任务
Guess saving a piece of muscle's not high on their priority list.
他们该重新考虑下任务的重要性了
They should rethink their priorities.
大块头气得想干架
Muscle's gonna be looking for a fight.
你觉得他会去找多米尼克算账
And you think he'll confront dominic?
我觉得他已经火冒三丈了
I think he's just mad enough to do it.
大块头是条小鱼  但他能引出大鱼
Our guy's a little fish, but he could lead us to the big one.
那就把小鱼放回去
So throw the minnow back.
你们俩准备好了吗
You two ready?
我们要冲了
Let's hit it.
我改主意了  我不想走
I changed my mind. I don't wanna go.
特蕾西  水枪还在吗
Tracie, do you still have your squirt gun?
太好了
Good.
可以备用
Could come in handy.
我们要玩躲猫猫
'cause we're gonna play hide and seek.
别担心
Don't worry.
这游戏我擅长
I'm really good at this game.
孩子躲在楼顶房间
Kids are holed up in the penthouse.
关掉摄像头
Kill the camera.
搞什么
What the--
这里
Down here.
这边  他们正往上来
This way. They're coming up.
都是我的错
This is all my fault.
警察在我妈那里搜到的枪
That gun the cops found on my mom...
是你的
It was yours.
妈妈撒了谎  说枪是她的
My mom lied. She said it belonged to her.
要不是我  她根本不会蹲监狱
She wouldn't even be in jail if it wasn't for me.
你要枪做什么  马尔科姆
Why'd you have a gun, Malcolm?
只是为了自保
Just wanted to protect my own.
却弄巧成拙
All I did was make it worse.
你说得对
You're right.
这是你的错
It is your fault.
但并非不能改正
Doesn't mean you can't make it right.
怎么做
How?
钱早没了
Money's long gone.
先逃出去  再来担心下边的事
Let's get out of here and we'll worry about the rest later.
走走走
Go, go, go.
看到他了吗  哈罗德
You got him, Harold?
他行动了
He's on the move.
令人钦佩  肖女士
I'm impressed, Ms. Shaw.
大块头很强悍啊
Yeah, big guy was strong,
亏还流了这么多血
considering how much blood he lost.
当然了  我还松了松管子
Course, I did loosen the pipes.
我指的是你放置了追踪设备
I was referring to how you were able to plant a tracking device
还没被他察觉
without our friend noticing.
我也给你安了  还有弗斯科
I planted one on you, Fusco...
靠  还有约翰呢  至今没被发现
Hell, even John. Haven't been caught yet.
我就不详询你的手法了
Remind me to stop inquiring about your modus operandi.
是他们
That's them.
快
Hurry.
别动
Don't move.
你就是那个算计我们的小子
You the dude that maced us?
对不起
Sorry.
没事的
It's okay.
-很快就会结束  -说得对
-It'll all be over soon. - You got that right.
把家伙滑过来  不然这小个儿开花
Slide that piece over here. Or shorty springs a leak.
淡定
Easy guys...
我是纽约警察
I'm NYPD.
我们知道你  莱利警探
We know who you are, Detective Riley.
见过我的搭档吗
Have you met my partner?
幸会啊
Nice to meet you.
真高兴你赶来了  莱纳尔
Glad you could make it, Lionel.
文件工作麻烦你了
Sorry about all the paperwork.
哥已经麻木了
Yeah, I'm getting used to it.
这些人没完没了啊
These guys don't quit.
我们永远不可能安全了
We ain't never gonna be safe.
带你妹妹躲起来
Take your sister and hide.
去
Go.
你还有几发
How many rounds you got?
希望足够
Enough, I hope.
孩子  别哭  你会没事的
Hey, kiddo, don't cry, you're gonna be okay.
我不是为这个哭
That's not why I'm crying.
我们应该永远在一起
We're supposed to stick together.
莱纳尔
Lionel...
马尔科姆人呢
Where's Malcolm?
当男子汉  得有计划
Wanna be the man, gotta have a plan.
你在里面吗
You in there?
你的话最好值得一听  小子
You better have something to say worth hearing, little man.
我有你想要的东西
I got something you want.
我想做个交易
I wanna make a trade.
我的命换我妹妹的
My life for my sister's.
快说重点
Best be getting to the point.
我的钱呢
Where's my money?
不在我这儿
I don't got it.
但我肯为你工作
But I'll work for you.
当你手下的混混
Be your corner boy,
给你顶罪  随便
Take a fall for you, whatever.
放过我妹妹
Just leave my sister be.
让他上来
Get him.
希望你告过别了
I hope you said your good-byes.
我想你忘了什么东西
I think you're forgetting something.
要钱吗
Do you want your money?
跟我交易
You deal with me.
我们回头再聊
We'll be catching up real soon.
我只想纠正错误
I was just trying to make it right.
不能用错误去纠正错误
You can't make something right by doing something wrong.
我向你保证过
I give you my word.
走  照顾好你妹妹
Go, you take care of your sister.
说完了  警探
You done, Detective?
咱们得好好叙叙旧
We got a lot of catching up to do.
长夜漫漫
Hell of a night for a drive.
没问题
He's clean.
咱别每次见面都这样啊
We have got to stop meeting like this.
慢慢转过身来
Turn around nice and slow.
你们来这儿不止是为了洗衣服吧
Maybe you guys do more than your laundry here.
我会交给你老大
I gotta hand it to your boss,
多米尼得想办法运走藏货了
Dominic's found a way to move a lot of smack.
你知道该干什么
You know the drill.
这里哪个角落最不显眼呢
Now where's the one place no one bothers to look?
知道不  今天是我的好日子啊
What do you know, it's my lucky day.
碰上买一赠一了
I got a twofer.
钱找回来了  还抓到了把我丢牢子里的人
Our money and the man that incarcerated me.
能拿着一个就很好了
I guess one out of two ain't bad.
钱呢
Where is it?
那你得去问伦诺克斯特工
You'll have to ask Agent Lennox.
不过她可能已经在去加勒比的路上了
'Cause, she's probably half way to the Caribbean by now.
还有你啊
You're still here.
子弹我多得是
And I got enough brass to spare.
今天还是我的好日子
Like I said, it's my lucky day.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我等这电话等好久了
I've been expecting this.
钓鱼钓得怎么样
How was the fishing trip?
没找到多米尼克
Came up empty on Dominic.
不过  我另有发现
But--uh-- I found something else
你的朋友应该有兴趣听听
your friends might be interested in.
给你的
It's for you.
搞什么鬼
Who the hell is this?
谈判会
The negotiation party.
放了莱利警官  不许再纠缠布克兄妹
Release Detective Riley and forget about the Booker kids.
我要是不答应呢
What if I don't?
那我就会伐开心  要烧房子
Or I huff, and I puff, and I burn your house down.
我想你也不希望老大知道
But I don't think you wanna tell your boss
你眼睁睁地看着他的藏货化为灰烬吧
that you watched his stash go up in flames, now, do you?
我可以放警探走
Say I let the detective go...
但你凭什么保证你就不会动手
how do I know you're gonna back off?
我给你留份分手礼物
I'll leave you a parting gift.
迷你陪着你的毒品
Mini here can keep your drugs company.
看来今天不是你的好日子啊
Guess it's not your lucky day after all.
你没说你为谁干活儿
Never said who you worked for.
没错  我没说过
You're right. I didn't.
告诉你老大  回见
Tell your boss I'll be seeing him soon.
上学真的没问题吗
You sure you're okay to go to school?
我都说了  你没事  我就没事
Told you. I'm okay if you're okay.
你和我  我们要永远在一起  对吗
You and me. We stick together, remember?
好  明天见
All right, see you tomorrow.
你去哪儿了
Where you been?
你以后每天都能见到特蕾西了
Actually, you'll be seeing Tracie later today.
我和你的社工谈了谈
I had a little chat with you social worker.
今天你就会被接到一个新家  你们俩
You've been assigned a new home together.
厉害
Impressive.
当你死了呢
For a dead man.
林克怎么会放你走
How'd you get Link to let you go?
我很有说服力啊
Turns out I can be pretty persuasive.
说到这个
Speaking of which...
我帮你联系了一名律师
I got you a consultation with a lawyer.
高手  哈佛毕业的
Dream team. Harvard law.
莱丝丽·奎尔
我有很多材料可以给她
Got a few articles I could send her.
莱恩杰·罗姆一案  还有布莱恩·艾肯一案
The people versus Ryan Jerome, or the Brian D. Aitken's case.
前者为强奸  后者为抚养权案
知道吗  马尔科姆
You know what, Malcolm?
我觉得你一定能成为一个好律师
I think you'd make a good lawyer.
我还想当警察呢
I was thinking about being a cop.
真的吗
Is that right?
就像你  不过我会少突突人
Like you, but I'd shoot less people.
当男子汉  得有计划
Wanna be the man, gotta have a plan.
友情提醒
As a friendly reminder,
请乘客们站在黄色安全线后候车
all passengers, please stand beind the yellow line.
这里有人坐吗
This seat taken?
这是个自由的世界
It's a free world.
起码曾经是
At least it used to be.
有心事吗  哈罗德
Something troubling you, Harold?
上次见面时  你问了我个问题
The last time we met, you asked me a question.
而你撒谎了
And you lied.
我怕真相会陷你于致命危险
I'm afraid the truth would put you in grave danger.
原来你这么关心我  哈罗德
I didn't know you cared, Harold.
我经常有致命危险
I've been in danger before.
不  这次完全不同
No, this is something altogether different.
我只能说  你说对了
All I can say is, you are right.
这世界已经改变
The world has changed.
看来是回不去了
I suppose there's no going back.
所以我来找你
Which brings me to the reason I came.
《隐身人》  赫·乔·威尔斯
暗示吗  哈罗德
A hint, Harold?
多事之秋的一点建议
Advice for these troubled times.
还有一点答谢礼
And a little thank you.
纽约市阿斯托利亚36号大街  33-191
兄弟会的藏货地址  至少五小时前是
It's the location of the Brotherhood's stash house as of five hours ago.
毒品这会儿肯定转移了
No doubt, the drugs have been relocated by now.
不过我知道你热衷于调查对手
But I know how dedicated you are to studying your adversaries.
我猜你想知道我是否知道了多米尼克的身份
I suppose you'll want to know if I identify this Dominic.
我猜是的
I suppose.
时局变幻莫测啊
It's a tricky business.
这场游戏要在一团迷雾中玩
Playing a game in which you're unsure of the pieces.
而且这场游戏
And in this game,
恐怕根本输不起
I fear that losing is not an option.
靠  你是猫吧
Damn, you like a cat.
至少九条命
You got at least nine lives.
藏货应该是没保住吧
I was worried we gonna lose the stash though.
海洛因很安全  起码现在是
"H" is safe. For now.
那贱人逼你说出地址了
Bitch made you tell her the location?
那小妞一直跟踪我  甩不掉
Chick was tracking me. I couldn't shake her.
只能给她点真料  她才肯罢休
I had to lead her to something of value so she'd back off.
我想派人去救你  但是
I would have sent somebody for you, but...
但你只能听命行事
But you were just following orders.
希望他的叛徒也是如此
I wish his rat would have did the same.
她偷货时候被我抓个正着
I caught this chick stealing crumbs.
我可以解释
I can explain everything.
你们老大呢
Where's your boss?
你刚见到了
You just met him.
Every day I see you looking in?
他们总是低估你
They always underestimate you.
布克那孩子也偷了我们的东西
Booker kids stole from us, too.
那小子倒是挺有头脑
Little man's got a good head on his shoulders.
适合给我们干活
Kind of kid should be working for us.
做通他母亲的工作
Spring his mom.
让他知道谁才是背后老大
Make sure he knows who pulled the strings.
这小子会回来投奔我们的
Boy'll find his way back to us.
全心全意归顺
Hearts and minds.
那个警察莱利呢
What about that cop, Riley?
那贱人跟他一伙的
And that bitch that was helping him.
搞不懂他们到底在玩哪一套
Still trying to figure out what game they playing.
似乎是毫无章法
Seems like they not playing by no rule book.
那警察很危险
Cop's dangerous.
他跟我们没什么不同
But he's no different than us.
警察永远都有  黑帮也永不消亡
There'll always be cops, like there'll always be gangsters.
只有一条真理
Only one rule.
什么  多米尼克
What's that, Dominic?
我们最终都难逃一死
We all die in the end.
And your priest,he tried so hard
To get you turned